<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Lord Chancellor's petition to His Highness the Prince of Orange on his entrance into London</title>
            <author>Jeffreys, George Jeffreys, Baron, 1644 or 5-1689.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A46720</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing J528A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R24416</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">08175459</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 08175459</idno>
            <idno type="VID">41012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A46720)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 41012)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1233:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Lord Chancellor's petition to His Highness the Prince of Orange on his entrance into London</title>
                  <author>Jeffreys, George Jeffreys, Baron, 1644 or 5-1689.</author>
                  <author>William III, King of England, 1650-1702.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year 1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>"Ireland's wonders from the skies, or, A warning-piece to all Papists": p. 5-8.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Revolution of 1688.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="part">
            <pb facs="tcp:41012:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:41012:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <head>THE Lord Chancellor's PETITION To His Highneſs the Prince
of Orange, On his Entrance into London.</head>
            <opener>Most Humbly Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>THat your Petitioner, who was once Lord High Chancellor of
<hi>England,</hi> is now become the Loweſt of your Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicants; and from the
firſt and chiefeſt Councellor about the Throne, a miſera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Dejected
Captive in the <hi>Tower.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I do not preſume to juſtifie my Integri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, that would be an
Arrogance as black as my Crimes. I confeſs, I am as unworthy 
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:41012:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->to Live, as I am unwilling to
Die; and therefore I proſtrate my ſelf to the Foot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtool of your Grace
and Clemency, that Fountain of unparalell'd goodneſs, whence only Mercy can
flow, upon ſo Vile and Notorious a Delinquent.</p>
            <p>To Innumerate my Crimes, would be as numberleſs as the Enemies
I have created by them; nor will I preſume to Prophane your Sacred Ears with
ſo black a Catalogue, whoſe precious Minutes are more happily Imployed in
the weightier Affairs of the Nation; the Reſtitution of thoſe Laws and
Liberties which I, by my byaſs'd and Precipitate Council, endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd to
Subvert.</p>
            <p>What cou'd be more pernicious and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructive to the
Fundamental Laws of the Nation, than to Eſtabliſh a Power in the Monarch,
to diſpence with them?</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:41012:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->
            <p>Whet greater Inlet to <hi>Popery,</hi> than to take off the
<hi>Teſt</hi> and <hi>Penal Laws?</hi> What deeper ſtroke to the
<hi>Protestant Church,</hi> than to Erect a Court of <hi>Eccleſiaſtical
Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners,</hi> to pull down her Pillars? What ſharper Perſecution
of the Prelats, than by publiſhing an Arbitrary Declaration; for the
Non-obeying of which Illegal VVarrant, ſo many ſince have been treat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed as
Criminals in the <hi>Tower:</hi> Nor could there be a more Irregular Method
than the late Regulating of Corporations for a free Election of Parliament. In
all which, and many others, (to my Shame, I muſt confeſs) I have been all
along a principal Counſellor and Inſtrument.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Theſe (may it pleaſe your Highneſs) are the Crying
Crimes, which, were they yet greater, is in your Power to mitigate, 
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:41012:3"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->by your Interceſſions to
the</hi> Parliament, <hi>having already the</hi> King's <hi>Pardon. If you
vouchſafe this Mercy to an humble Supplicant, I will promiſe in ſome
meaſure to make Retaliation, by Diſcovering ſome</hi> Arcana Imperii,
<hi>or Intriegues of State, what I am Capable of; which may high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly concern
your Highneſs's Intereſt in this Kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:41012:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->
            <head>IRELANDS Wonders from the Skies: OR, A Warning-piece TO ALL
PAPISTS.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>WE have had ſo many Miracles of this Kind, Spectres &amp;
Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nonima's in the Air, that I would not of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer this Subject to the VVorld, if
I had not more than common Authority to confirm it. I will not inſiſt upon
the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of quality, from whom the Letter (which implys the Contents of
this Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per) was Communicated, nor inſtance the Perſon to whom it was
VVrit; tho' <pb n="6" facs="tcp:41012:4"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->of ſufficient
Credit, to affirm the Truth of what is inferred.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Letters bear date</hi> Novemb. <hi>the 18th wherein are
ſuch Prodigies expreſt, as wou'd exceed all Belief, if it had not
pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded from a perſon of ſo much integrity, and confirmed ſince by
ſo many perſons of undenyable Authority.</hi>
            </p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <head>The <hi>LETTER.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IN the Town of <hi>Youghall,</hi> near <hi>Kingſail,</hi> in
the County of <hi>Cork,</hi> upon the <hi>18th</hi> of <hi>Novemb.</hi> laſt,
about Nine of the Clock at Night, my Aunt, the Lady <hi>L.</hi> going to ſee
her Siſter, diſcover'd a ſtrange and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>expected Viſion, <hi>viz.</hi>
The <hi>Moon,</hi> which was then in her Encreaſe, all Red, with a croſs
Gules in the middle; upon which, being ſurpriſ'd, ſhe call'd her Servants
to be Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctators. This ſuddenly diſappearing, another 
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:41012:4"/>
                     <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->ſucceeded; which, changing
the former Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gure, bore the Emblem of a <hi>Lyon;</hi> By which time all the
Town being alarm'd, came out to behold this wond'rous Prodigy. No ſooner they
appear'd, but both thoſe Won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders diſappeared.</p>
                  <p>The two <hi>Moons,</hi> over-caſt with a dark Cloud,
appeared diſmal to the Speclators; when, on a ſudden, the Cloud diſperst,
and all the Firmament appear'd ſerene and clear. Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter this apeared a more
prodigious Spectre, <hi>viz.</hi> Two Armies, in viſible and diſtinctive
Habits, one <hi>Red</hi> and <hi>Blew,</hi> the other <hi>White</hi> and
<hi>Yellow;</hi> betwixt which two, ſeemed a moſt deep and deadly
Engagement; inſomuch that a ſhowre of Blood dropt from the ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thering
Clouds; but moſt diſcernable in the <hi>White</hi> and <hi>Yellow.</hi>
Afterwards the two <hi>Moons</hi> appear'd as viſible as before, with the
ſame Figure, till the morning; which put <pb n="8" facs="tcp:41012:5"/>
                     <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->a
period to the Combat, and drove us, (who were Spectators with Horror and
Amaze<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment) to our reſpective Habitations.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>The truth of this ſurpriſing Relation, is
teſtified by</hi> 
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Sir</hi> William Parry, <hi>Mayor.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Derras Hynde, <hi>Collector.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Thomas Osburn, <hi>Sheriff.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Robert Hapkins, <hi>Vimner.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Henry Davis, <hi>Church-Warden</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>William Dawſon, <hi>Miniſtor of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap> Town.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Thomas Davis, <hi>Town-Clark.</hi>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed in the Year, 1689.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:41012:5"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:41012:6"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:41012:6"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
